So this, um, this article that you're working on, Mr. Emery.
Yes, it's about technology.
Well, you certainly come to the right place.
I'm sure that Charles has filled you in on what we do here.
Don't have the wattage saying,
I thought it best to leave that to you.
Oh.
Well, um, I work on advanced packet switching data systems,
a single communications link that collects information
into datagrams and then transmits them onto an attached network.
Um, sort of like a handshake that introduces distant computers
to each other in virtual space.
Virtual space?
Uh, you're familiar with the post office?
Sure.
Yes.
Okay, so let's say that you have a friend in Japan named Hirohito.
Hirohito lives in a tiny remote fishing village in Japan,
and he wants to send you a postcard,
but Hirohito only knows Japanese and, well, you don't read Japanese.
So he sends his postcard to the Japanese post office,
which translates the postcard into a universal post office language.
A code.
A code, exactly.
And is the post office in Japan?
Uh, Japan, Johannesburg, Bangkok, Rio, anywhere and everywhere.
It's sort of like God, you know, except without the big beard
and the flowing white robes.
But unlike the Japanese post office, which is, of course, in Japan,
God resides...
In heaven.
In heaven, exactly.
In heaven, as we all know, is...
The PDP-10, more as we affect some refer to it as,
the beast can run multiple operating systems,
10X, TICOMX, ITS, weights, tops, 20, etc., etc.,
simultaneously.
And that's where what happens?
Creation.
Okay, but not quite.
The information generated by the beast still needs to be disseminated.
It can be sort of likely pollen in the wind.
And that happens, well, in another room.
Think of the beast as your disembodied brain,
the machine that services your brain,
that translates a postcard written in any one of 116 languages known to man
into a universal code instantaneously,
that allows it to share its thoughts and feelings
across a vast network as large as potentially the university itself
that keeps it communicative.
The interface message processor.
We have our very own imp.
It is, in a manner of speaking, the interstate highway system
through which all information flows.
What kind of information?
Anything.
And everything shared on the network.
And who's on the network?
Scientists.
And mathematicians.
Universities.
The military.
The military and scientific community share the same network.
For now.
So the imp is like a traffic cop?
Traffic cop.
Facilitator.
Translator.
Keeping information moving with no snafus,
no tie ups on an endless ribbon of virtual highway.
Going where?
To the future.